<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Nick</title>
    <link>https://nearwood.dev/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Nick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Nicholas Earwood</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 02:13:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nearwood.dev/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Education in Futility: WarpWallet Brute Forcing</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/education-in-futility-warpwallet-brute-forcing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 02:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/education-in-futility-warpwallet-brute-forcing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/warp/warp_1.0.9_SHA256_a2067491ab582bde779f4505055807c2479354633a2216b22cf1e92d1a6e4a87.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WarpWallet&lt;/a&gt; is a so-called brain wallet for Bitcoin. That is, you only have to remember a relatively short password and it generates the corresponding private key for use. It uses a memory and CPU hard set of cryptographic algorithms to ensure that brute-forcing is slowed way down. That is, when generating the private key, it takes considerable time. Their Javascript implementation takes over 10 seconds on my machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the makers of it had challenges setup. By the time I stumbled on it, only the last challenge was left, with 6 months remaining. For that challenge, the reward for cracking an 8-character alphanumeric password was 20 BTC (and BCH and BTG!), which was worth over $100,000 USD at the time of the challenge end date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering the firmware on a Kenwood DDX9903S</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/reverse-engineering-the-firmware-on-a-kenwood-ddx9903s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 03:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/reverse-engineering-the-firmware-on-a-kenwood-ddx9903s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE 14 MAR 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: For discussion, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/kenwood-headunit-reverse-engineering&#34;&gt;Google group&lt;/a&gt;. Comments from the old WordPress site have been migrated there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought and really like my Kenwood Excelon DDX9903S headunit. I had it in my WRX, and moved it to my LS430. It supports Android Auto and CarPlay, which I find really useful when driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it has a nag screen every time it boots up. This got me curious as to how it worked, and see if it could be patched to skip this disclaimer. I figured it probably ran Linux on a SoC, as pretty much everything does nowadays. So I grabbed the latest firmware for it (mine was already updated to it), and started probing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;S_V2_7_0008_0600_AT1.zip&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extract that and you get 3 folders under S_V2_7_0008_0600/:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;brush: plain; light: true; title: ; notranslate&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;BOOT_V2_7_0008_0600_release/
MAIN_V1_0_2758_0400/
SOC_V2_7_0008_0600/
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo Linux Tesla – It was only a matter of time…</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/gentoo-linux-tesla-it-was-only-a-matter-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 22:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/gentoo-linux-tesla-it-was-only-a-matter-of-time/</guid>
      <description>Surprise, surprise, my old favorite Gentoo Linux is now running on a Tesla Model S. Hope he doesn&amp;rsquo;t emerge world while driving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Robot – Assembly Part 2</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/raspberry-pi-robot-assembly-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 01:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/raspberry-pi-robot-assembly-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This was the hardest part. If you wire the wrong things together you can brick your Pi. I took some time to decide on which pins to use, and after assembly and testing everything worked. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain which pins I picked, but note that this information will not work with other hardware configurations.[I originally had a Model B Pi, but due to needing the second hardware PWM (which is hidden on the B), switched to the B+.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oculus Rift and Touch</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/oculus-rift-and-touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/oculus-rift-and-touch/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m super excited for the imminent onslaught of consumer grade VR equipment and game support. I think it will change how games are played from now on. Not all games, mind you, it takes a certain level of involvement to strap on a head-mounted display and get into the experience. The military already uses similar technology extensively for training. It&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of months before equipment hits shelves.
That said, there&amp;rsquo;s a serious problem with it already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Action Camera Review: Garmin Virb Elite</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/action-camera-review-garmin-virb-elite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 02:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/action-camera-review-garmin-virb-elite/</guid>
      <description>After seeing a fellow MSNE autocrosser post a video with nice data overlays, I asked what datalogger and software he used. It turns out it wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a data logger, it was a camera that gathered his speed, acceleration, and so on for him. It was the Garmin Virb Elite. The &amp;lsquo;Elite&amp;rsquo; part signifying the difference between the non-sensor, data-less variant.
I&amp;rsquo;d never heard of it, and I thought I kept at least a cursory eye on the action camera market.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>