<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>automotive on Nick</title>
    <link>https://nearwood.dev/tags/automotive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in automotive on Nick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Nicholas Earwood</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 00:10:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nearwood.dev/tags/automotive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3.3L 280Z Runs</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/3-3l-280z-runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 00:10:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/3-3l-280z-runs/</guid>
      <description>So, am I the first? The first to put a VG33 in an S30? I have doubts but I&#39;ve never heard of it before. After a bit of late night work and an unplanned oil event and a small unplanned fuel dump after removing and replacing the engine to fix the oil leak, it&#39;s back in, running, and more importantly: not leaking.
Here&#39;s a late night in-progress shot:
 All the work was worth it, I had to get it running for a scheduled photoshoot:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>280Z SpeedHut gauge conversion</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/280z-speedhut-gauge-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 01:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/280z-speedhut-gauge-conversion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I acquired some Speedhut gauges a while back for a deal, and I just got a free 240Z wheel, so I decided to do all three. In this part I just remove and fit the Speedhut gauges in the old speedo and tachometer housings. In the next part I wire them up. A few people did this on HybridZ various different ways. I was too cheap to go out and get any other supplies, so I made it work with what I had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gauges I got are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speedometer: 4&amp;rdquo; Revolution GPS Speedo with integrated fuel gauge, turn signal LEDs, and high-beam LED&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tachometer: 4&amp;rdquo; Revolution 8,000RPM with programmable shift LEDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both have red dials, and red illumination. The fuel gauge is there since I&#39;ll be replacing the one in the 3 small dash gauges eventually, but don&#39;t want to lose having a gas gauge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;lostImage&#34; src=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;Image no longer available :(&#34;/&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>