<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cryptocurrency on Nick</title>
    <link>https://nearwood.dev/tags/cryptocurrency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cryptocurrency on Nick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Nicholas Earwood</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 02:13:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nearwood.dev/tags/cryptocurrency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Education in Futility: WarpWallet Brute Forcing</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/education-in-futility-warpwallet-brute-forcing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 02:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/education-in-futility-warpwallet-brute-forcing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/warp/warp_1.0.9_SHA256_a2067491ab582bde779f4505055807c2479354633a2216b22cf1e92d1a6e4a87.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WarpWallet&lt;/a&gt; is a so-called brain wallet for Bitcoin. That is, you only have to remember a relatively short password and it generates the corresponding private key for use. It uses a memory and CPU hard set of cryptographic algorithms to ensure that brute-forcing is slowed way down. That is, when generating the private key, it takes considerable time. Their Javascript implementation takes over 10 seconds on my machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the makers of it had challenges setup. By the time I stumbled on it, only the last challenge was left, with 6 months remaining. For that challenge, the reward for cracking an 8-character alphanumeric password was 20 BTC (and BCH and BTG!), which was worth over $100,000 USD at the time of the challenge end date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAWMiner Fury</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/gawminer-fury/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/gawminer-fury/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m attempting to jump on the Scrypt based ASIC coin mining bandwagon. I got a GAWMiner Fury to try out. It came with a free ZenMiner, which is a Raspberry Pi with a custom image that runs mining software automatically, and connects to a 3rd party website to allow remote control and monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_354&#34; style=&#34;width: 310px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;lostImage&#34; src=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;Image no longer available :(&#34;/&gt;
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    GAWMiner Fury and ZenMiner
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It came with everything needed to power up and get started. The included instructions just mention how to get started using the ZenMiner, so it&amp;rsquo;s pretty skimpy compared to most other packaged products. Being an ASIC cryptocurrency miner, it&amp;rsquo;s already a specialty device so you likely know what you are doing. Still, the ZenMiner is geared to newcomers so they can easily start mining. In that respect I think it still needs work as the ZenOS web interface is pretty but limited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>