<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Nick</title>
    <link>https://blog.nearwood.net/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Nick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Nicholas Earwood</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 00:10:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.nearwood.net/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Backup</title>
      <link>https://blog.nearwood.net/windows-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 00:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nearwood.net/windows-backup/</guid>
      <description>After installing Windows 7 in place of OS X on my MacBook Pro for work, there are only a few things I miss. But man, they were really nice.
 Unix shell Time Machine  The first one I&amp;#8217;ll just say if you haven&amp;#8217;t used a Unix-like shell of some type (Bash, zsh, whatever) then it&amp;#8217;s hard to explain. Just that you can do everything a GUI can do (save for graphics work), but much, much faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows bugs</title>
      <link>https://blog.nearwood.net/windows-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 13:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nearwood.net/windows-bugs/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I&amp;#8217;ve noticed a couple bugs that are present in in some or all of NT/Vista/7. I experience these on a daily basis, across dozens of computers. So it can&amp;#8217;t just be me, right?
 Focus bug. If the timing is right, some windows remain on top despite clicking on a background window. The background window obtains focus, but does not move to the front. This is typically when the foreground window does some focus changing action (Showing a dialog, opening a new tab, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This PC loves Adobe</title>
      <link>https://blog.nearwood.net/this-pc-loves-adobe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 00:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nearwood.net/this-pc-loves-adobe/</guid>
      <description>So much, that it installed multiple copies of the same Flash updates:

Actually, it appears to be a registry glitch rather than multiple copies. As much as I don&amp;#8217;t like Adobe&amp;#8217;s updating/installation practices (opted-in toolbars, programs), they do have a relatively easy to find and use Flash removal application.
&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QEMU on Windows</title>
      <link>https://blog.nearwood.net/posts/2012-07-05-qemu-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 01:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nearwood.net/posts/2012-07-05-qemu-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>After fumbling around with various downloads and patches, I was able to find a working QEMU build for windows. I am running Windows 7 64-bit, and I wanted to run an ARM system (specifically, to develop for a Stratus plug computer). Before this, I was running a virtualized Ubuntu using VirtualBox and then running QEMU within that. Performance was not noticeably bad.
However, I had problems bridging the QEMU to the Ubuntu host, which was bridged itself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>