<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>welding on Nick</title>
    <link>https://nearwood.dev/tags/welding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in welding on Nick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Nicholas Earwood</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 17:01:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nearwood.dev/tags/welding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Harbor Freight Trailer Build</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/harbor-freight-trailer-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 17:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/harbor-freight-trailer-build/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve got this autocross bug, despite being a terrible driver. After about 5 seconds of thought, I came to the conclusion that I must get an autocross trailer in order to improve my skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after a bit of research it looked like item #90153 was the thing to get. The key is it has 12&amp;rdquo; wheels, whereas the cheaper one (#42708) has 8&amp;rdquo; ones. The larger the wheel the less RPM the wheel bearings see, which is good. The increased payload capacity and trailer height were just bonuses. Since I plan on hauling some wheels and tires and some tools, I don&amp;rsquo;t see coming near the 1000+ lb. payload capacity. And if you wanted to carry more, all you&amp;rsquo;d really need is some better tires, since that&amp;rsquo;s the actual limiting factor. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend carrying anything near the payload capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that this is one of the few big-ticket items you can use the 20% coupon on, so if you want to save $46 or so off the price, use one! I got it and built it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-auto alignnone&#34; src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/2yDVaX2l.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;387&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also picked up a trailer jack, LED lighting kit, 1-&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;&amp;rdquo; ball, and ratcheting straps from HF. From elsewhere I got a backup alarm, more LED lights, battery tray, some wire and a voltage gauge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then painted the frame and wheels to match my 280Z:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-auto alignnone&#34; src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/8PgwmRvl.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>