<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gentoo on Nick</title>
    <link>https://nearwood.dev/tags/gentoo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gentoo on Nick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Nicholas Earwood</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 22:07:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nearwood.dev/tags/gentoo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo Linux Tesla – It was only a matter of time…</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/gentoo-linux-tesla-it-was-only-a-matter-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 22:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/gentoo-linux-tesla-it-was-only-a-matter-of-time/</guid>
      <description>Surprise, surprise, my old favorite Gentoo Linux is now running on a Tesla Model S. Hope he doesn&amp;rsquo;t emerge world while driving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switched to Arch Linux from Gentoo</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/switched-to-arch-linux-from-gentoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 12:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/switched-to-arch-linux-from-gentoo/</guid>
      <description>Time installing Gentoo: days
Time installing Archlinux: 30 mins.
I have an old Intel based Dell laptop with 1.8GHz single-core processor. I&amp;rsquo;ve had Windows XP on it for a couple years, then I switched to Gentoo for the past 5 or 6 years. Well, it&amp;rsquo;s really not the kind of laptop that you should be compiling everything from source on. I&amp;rsquo;m tired of going through the &amp;ldquo;everything&amp;rsquo;s broken, hook it the ethernet cable and start fixing it&amp;rdquo; routine after I&amp;rsquo;ve left it alone for months at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>udev broke, server broke, router broke</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/udev-broke-server-broke-router-broke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 02:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/udev-broke-server-broke-router-broke/</guid>
      <description>I attempted to get a webcam going on our home server. So, I plug it in, and since I&amp;rsquo;ve done this before I ran a script I made to grab an image from the webcam. Which didn&amp;rsquo;t work. So, after checking out why (/dev/video0 node was missing), I noticed that the kernel no longer had support built in.
After going through the kernel options, I realized they changed the v4l and webcam support options around and since I just upgrade using &amp;ldquo;-silentoldconfig&amp;rdquo; (the bad way to do upgrades), it broke whenever I upgraded to 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home server is back online</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/home-server-is-back-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 01:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/home-server-is-back-online/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve pulled power and cable from the attic and just powered up the home server again. It&amp;rsquo;s been asleep for 5 months until now. I&amp;rsquo;ve just done an emerge -sync, and it took about 10 minutes to complete.
However, it went up without any problems, which is good. Considering I turned it off in a working state. I was tempted to backup all my config files and start fresh with, say, Arch Linux, but that would take all weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo on a mid-2012 MacBook Pro</title>
      <link>https://nearwood.dev/gentoo-on-a-mid-2012-macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 05:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nearwood.dev/gentoo-on-a-mid-2012-macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>If your sick of your brand new MacBook just working (more or less), and you just feel like modifying your kernel&amp;rsquo;s source to get your computer to work right, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place. I (finally) managed to get Gentoo booting on a new MacBook Pro (15&amp;rdquo;, Core i7, mid-2012) alongside OS X 10.8.2. I suppose it actually wasn&amp;rsquo;t that bad, it could have been much worse. I only had to reinstall OS X once after a wonky partition editor&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>